Whitman Family Correspondence, 1808-1867
Connecticut Historical Society
Whitman Family Correspondence
1808-1867
Connecticut Historical Society, Hartford, Connecticut
Whitman Family
0.5 linear feet (1 box)
Biographical Sketch
Captain Samuel Whitman (1753-1810), a Revolutionary War soldier, was born in West Hartford where he lived with his wife Abigail Abbott Whitman (1762-1844). Their oldest son Samuel (1786-1888) married Elizabeth Howard and lived in West Hartford where he was devoted to breeding fine sheep and serving with the Governor’s Horse Guard. The other children in the family included Eliza (1788-1812), Abigail (1789-1812) who married Timothy Goodman, Henry (1791-1812), Emma who died young, Lucy (1797-1831) who married Avelyn Sedgwick and settled in Ogden, NY, Harriet (1799-1850) who married Epaphras Goodman, Timothy’s brother and a minister, Emeline (1801-1825), Julia (1803-1864) and Laura (1807-1833). Samuel and Elizabeth Howard Whitman had children Henry Lyman, George Abbott, Eliza (b. 1819). Myrtle, Charlotte, Samuel (b. 1823), Emeline (b. 1826) and John (b. 1828). Additional information on the family can be found in the collection folder in the archivist’s office and in the Whitman genealogy.
Scope and Content
The collection consists almost entirely of correspondence among the members of the Whitman, Goodman and Sedgwick families concerning family and neighborhood news. There are a few other documents, namely some rewards of merit for good school work, several compositions and poems, and a memorandum book kept by one of the Samuel Whitmans.
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions on access to the collection.
Accruals
The collection is closed.
Subject Headings
Personal Names
Whitman family.; Goodman, Abigail Whitman, 1789-1812.; Goodman, Epaphras, 1790-1862.; Goodman, Harriet Whitman, 1799-1850.; Goodman, Timothy, 1787-1869.; Sedgwick, Avelyn 1793-1868.; Sedgwick, Lucy Whitman, 1797-1831.; Whitman, Abigail Abbott, 1762-1844.; Whitman, Eliza, 1788-1812.; Whitman, Emeline, 1801-1825.; Whitman, Henry, 1791-1812.; Whitman, John b. 1828.; Whitman, Julia, 1803-1864.; Whitman, Laura, 1807-1833.; Whitman, Samuel, 1786
Subjects
Family networks --Connecticut --West Hartford.; West Hartford (Conn.) --History --Sources.
Contents:
- Papers
  - Abigail Whitman from Avelyn Sedgwick, 1823-1838 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Abigail Whitman from Lucy Whitman Sedgwick, 1829 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Abigail Whitman from Emeline Whitman and from Harriet and Epaphras Goodman, 1829-1842 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Samuel Whitman from Timothy Goodman, 1810 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Samuel Whitman from Henry Whitman, 1813 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Samuel Whitman from Harriet and Epaphras Goodman, 1830-1850 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Samuel Whitman from Avelyn Sedgwick, 1836-1849 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Samuel Whitman from Julia Whitman, 1845-1862 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Eliza Whitman from Henry Whitman and L. Montague, 1809-1814 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Abigail Whitman from Eliza Whitman, 1811 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Abigail Whitman poem, before 1812 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Henry Whitman from Eliza Whitman, 1813-1814 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Henry Whitman from Timothy Whitman and Orville Deming, 1814 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Harriet Whitman Goodman from her sisters Lucy and Julia, from Avelyn Sedgwick and from her husband Epaphras Goodman, 1826-1845 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Emeline Whitman school composition and rewards of merit letters from friends and from Harriet Whitman Goodman, 1819,1821-1825 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Julia Whitman award of merit, undated, and probate document, 1864 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Julia Whitman from sisters Emeline, Harriet Goodman, Lucy Sedgwick, Avelyn Sedgwick, Epaphras Goodman, and Harriet Thompson Sedgwick, 1819-1842, undated (Box 1, Folder 17-20)
  - Laura Whitman from sisters Julia, Lucy Sedgwick and Harriet Goodman, 1825-1833 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Eliza Whitman from Abigail Whitman and aunts Harriet and Helen Goodman, 1830-1860 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - John Whitman from Emma Arnold and Samuel Goodman, 1864-1867 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Assorted Whitman and Goodman correspondence, 1808-1862 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Assorted documents, 1815-ca. 1850 (Box 1, Folder 25)